Inventory of the Joseph Breckinridge Bayne papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Joseph Breckinridge Bayne papers
1917-1935
67013
Hoover Institution Archives
1 manuscript box, 1 envelope (0.5 linear feet)
Clippings, other printed matter, photocopies of letters, certificates, and photographs, relating to military and civilian hospitals in Romania during World War I, and to postwar conditions in Romania.
Bayne, Joseph Breckinridge, 1880-1964.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1967.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the library catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
American physician; surgeon with the Romanian Red Cross, 1916-1918.
Scope and Content of Collection
Clippings, other printed matter, photocopies of letters, certificates, and photographs, relating to military and civilian hospitals in Romania during World War I, and to postwar conditions in Romania.
Societatea Nationala de Cruce Rosie.; World War, 1914-1918--Medical care.; World War, 1914-1918--Romania.
- Biographical information, newspaper clippings, and photocopied correspondence, 1917-1919, undated (Box-folder 1: 1-2)
- Newspaper clippings, circa 1917-1919, 1924
  - General, World War I, circa 1917-1919 (Box-folder 1: 3-4)
  - Queen Marie of Romania, circa 1917-1919 (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - Romanian Royal Family, circa 1917-1919 (Box-folder 1: 6-8)
  - Romania at war, circa 1917-1919 (Box-folder 1: 9-11)
  - Red Cross work in Romania, circa 1917-1919 (Box-folder 1: 12)
  - Romanian newspapers, 1919 (Box-folder 1: 13)
  - Romania, general, 1924 (Box-folder 1: 14)
- Printed Matter, 1919-1920
  - Calendrul de Rasbou al Ostasilov Români, 1919 (Box-folder 1: 15)
  - Peasant Cooperation and Agrarian Reform in Romania, by M.M. Knight, 1920 (Box-folder 1: 16)
- Certificates, 1918-1919, 1935 (Box-folder 1: 17)
- Photographs
  - Photographs and negatives depicting the Red Cross Commission to Romania, food relief distribution, Bilcuresti, Romania, and copies of photographs of Queen Marie of Romania signed by her and dedicated to Dr. Bayne and of Queen Marie visiting Dr. Bayne of the American Red Cross Unit Working in the typhus epidemic district in Bucharest, Romania May 4, 1919 (Box-folder 1: Envelope A)
  - Portrait photograph of Dr. Bayne (oversize) (Envelope mB)